shoyeb.engineer | LinkedIn | GitHub | Leetcode

Location: New Town, Kolkata, West Bengal Email: shoyebmd424@gmail.com | Mobile: +91 9871904481

SUMMARY

I am a skilled web developer with over 11 months of experience as a intern & freelancing in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Node Js. I have knowledge of Data structure and algorithm with 3* in Leetcode and popular frameworks such as React, Bootstrap, Node Js, and Express Js and experience with REST APIs and MVC frameworks.

EXPERIENCE

FreelancingAragsa

Mar 2022 – Nov 2022

Remote

- I was create from scratch to advanced and after completing that also be maintaining
- Designed, developed and deploy dynamic and responsive websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Rest APIs, React
 Js MongoDB, Node Js, Github Action, pip-lining
- Setup Virtual Private Server (VPS) using ubuntu for the deploy website on the cloud

Android Developer Aug 2022 – Oct 2022

Google Supported Virtual Internship

Remote

- Worked with Kotlin to develop UI / UX of two project one is Grocery App and Near By place App using google map API
- Troubleshot and fixed bugs and issues in the backend to ensure smooth operation of the applications

EDUCATION

Aliah University
New Town, kolkata, West Bengal, India
B.Tech in Electronics and Communication engineering || Current CPI 7.6 cgpa
Jan 2020 – Dec 2023

Jamia Millia Islamia University

Diploma in Electronics and Communication engineering || Current CPI 84%

New Delhi, Delhi, India Jan 2017 – Dec 2020

PROJECTS

E Commerce AppHTML,CSS ,Bootstrap, React Js, Context API, Node Js, Express js, Mongo DB
Project Link

• It is a basic e-commerce site which build in MERN tech stack. It has all the functionality which is required in e-commerce site with User dashboard ,admin dashboard and different role authentication login

Video Calling App React Js, Node Js, Git, WEB RTC Project Link

• A Video-Chat Application where users could talk and chat with each other in real-time.

Hotel Booking React Js, Node Js, Express, JavaScript, Git Project Link

- Hotel managing app Book rooms on different locations and Exposed POST, GET, PATCH and DELETE HTTP methods
 using Express
- A CRUD application exposed using a RESTful API made with Node.js and Authentication with different role using jwt

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Object oriented programming | Data structure and algorithms | Design and Analysis of algorithms | Git&Github

Languages : JavaScript, Java, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: React Js, Bootstrap, Express, Node Js

Libraries : Material, Redux, React Router

Databases : MongoDB, MYSQL

CERTIFICATIONS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- 3* & 300+ questions Leetocode |350+ questions Geeks for geeks
- Global Rank 1259 in Starter 83 Challenging on CodeChef.
- Certificate of Participation in Level 1: E-Commerce